A Guide to the Randolph Huntington Correspondence and Ephemera, 1833; 1876-1908
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Randolph Huntington Correspondence and Ephemera, 1833; 1876-1908
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11844
This collection consists of correspondence and ephemera, ca. 2,600 items (13 Hollinger boxes, ca. 5 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the University of Virginia Library from L & T. Respess, Charlottesville, Virginia, on March 9, 2001.
Biographical/Historical Information
Randolph Huntington was a New York City pharmaceutical manufacturer who moved to central New York state after the Civil War to breed and sell fine saddle and coach horses and who became a leading American authority on the Arabian horse.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of correspondence and ephemera, ca. 2,600 items (13 Hollinger boxes, ca. 5 linear feet), 1833; 1876-1908, from the estate of Randolph Huntington. The papers contain letters from breeders and owners of Arab horses, editors and writers for sporting periodicals of the period, and correspondents with others interested in horses; printed ephemera (transferred to the Rare Books Division); and material documenting the publication of Huntington's book, History of Leopard & Linden, General Grant's Arabian Stallions.
Huntington became interested in using the two stallions given to former President U.S. Grant in 1877 by the Sultan of Turkey to breed a national horse for the United States. His breeding project, based on the Grant stallions and mares out of the trotting horse Henry Clay, was not successful but it did bring the value of Arabian blood to the attention of other American horsemen, most notably Homer Davenport. There are three letters from Daisy Davenport, Homer Davenport's wife, to Huntington in the correspondence.
Highlights of the collection include Huntington's Library of Congress copyright form for his book, signed by A.R. Spofford, the Librarian of Congress; a small group of correspondence from the book's publisher, Lippincott, 1885; and a group of approximately fifty letters from Spencer Borden, author of The Arab Horse(New York, 1906). Much of the correspondence pertains in some way to the history, breeding, raising, racing, or showing of the Arabian horse in the United States.
Arrangement
These letters are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent, with more frequent correspondents placed in their own folders. The financial papers, news clippings, pedigrees, reviews, and other miscellaneous material has been placed after the correspondence in the last box.
Contents List
- Correspondence - A 1877-1890 (Box 1)
  Correspondents include: Edward L. Adams, E. Agnew, Frederick Akers, Charles N. Almy, M.B. Anderson, E.P. Andrews, William L. Annis, George W. Archer, Argus Press clipping Bureau, A.R. Ashley, Austin & Kohl, A.C. Austin
  alphabetical
- Correspondence - Thomas B. Armitage 1883-1887 (Box 1)
  Arranged alphabetically.
- Correspondence - Avedis G. Asdikian 1888-1890, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence - B to Baxter 1879-1888 (Box 1)
  Correspondents include: Charles Babbidge, Charles Backman, John M. Bailey, David Baird, George B. Baker, Ira C. Baker, W.J. Baker, C.H. Barbour, Dell Barker, M.I. Barker, L.B. Bartholomew, J. Battele, G.S. Battey, Isaac A. Baxter
- Correspondence - Beale to Bush 1880-1903 (Box 1)
  Correspondents include: E.F. Beale, O.D. Beebe, H.V. Bemis of The Chicago Horseman, Mr. and Mrs. Bend, Peter Benedict, J.D. Benham, C.D. Bennett, H. Bennett, L.S. Birdlong, H.R. Bishop, S. L. Boardman, Robert Bonner, A. Bordwell, Fred H. Bowker, E.R. Bowne, C. [Waude?] Bozart, A.S. Braman, C.D. Bray, George Bristane, F.H. Britt, Lou H. Brown, L.W. Bruce, Sanders D. Bruce, E.R. Budd, C.C. Buel, Frank W. Burns, Emory Busby, A.L. Bush, C.A. Bush
- Correspondence - Clinton Babbitt, secretary of the State of Wisconsin Agricultural Society 1883-1884 (Box 1)
- Correspondence - E. Folsom Baker 1890-1891, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence - James E. Bathgate of Newark Beef Company 1901-1903, 3 folders (Box 2)
- Correspondence - William E. Beames of F.P. Freeman & Company 1878-1894 (Box 2)
- Correspondence - James C. Beecher 1886-1889 (Box 2)
- Correspondence - Clark Bell of Bell, Bartlett & Wilson, Attorneys and Counsellors at Law 1879 (Box 2)
- Correspondence - J.P. and M.H. Blackmer 1882-1891 (Box 2)
- Correspondence - Spencer Borden of Fall River Bleachery Company 1890-1905, 2 folders (Box 2)
  Borden is author of The Arab Horse(New York, 1906)
- Correspondence - John T. Brawhall 1890-1901 (Box 2)
  Brawhall is on the staff of the Albany Evening Journal
- Correspondence - J.T. Brown 1882 & 1887 (Box 2)
  Brown was the proprietor of Gorham House, includes Huntington's note: This is the man who raised Captain Lewis (1882 Oct 3)
- Correspondence - Charles H. Brush 1903-1904 (Box 2)
- Correspondence - George E. Bryant 1883-1898, 2 folders (Box 2)
  Bryant was the U.S. Postmaster, Madison, Wisconsin and secretary of Dane County Agricultural Society in Wisconsin
- Correspondence - George E. Bryant, Jr. 1882-1889 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - E.A. Buck and H.A. Buck, editors of The Spirit of the Times 1880-1897 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - J.J. Bush 1888-1889 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - C to Coe 1882-1891 (Box 3)
  Correspondents include: Henry T. Carr, Peter D. Carroll, D.D. Carter, The Century Company and Magazine, James Chambers, C.A. Chapman, R.B. Chouler of Turf, Field and Farm and American Turf Register, W.H. Cisco, Pickering H. Clark, Henry Clews, Henry M. Codding, Amos D. Coe
- Correspondence - Cole to Cushing 1881-1902 (Box 3)
  Correspondents include: George H. Cole, James W. Colt, Henry W. Conklin, W.H. Cook, W.A. Cooper, A.Corbin, Jr., F.C. Cornell, Bruce Cornwall, William Cox, C.O.H. Craigie, Gilbert T. Crisfield, Frank Crocker, T.A. Crooks, J. Crouch, Edward Crundall, W.C. Cruser, publisher of The Democrat, X.W. Culbertson, Brook Curry, Charles G. Cushing
- Correspondence - W.J. Carter 1885-1886 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Walter T. Chester of The Spirit of the Times and Chester's Complete Trotting and Pacing Record 1882-1889 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - William N. Clark of Schieffelin & Company 1886-1902 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Thornton Cleard 1903 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Fred H. Cleaveland and J.M. Cleaveland 1901-1902 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Collier's Weekly1901 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - A.G. Collins of The Saint James Livery 1883-1887 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Erastus Corning 1879-1884 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - W.D.G. Cottrell, Banker 1885-1899 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - James W. Cox, Jr. 1883-1885, 2 folders (Box 3)
- Correspondence - James W. Cox, Jr. 1886-1897, 5 folders (Box 4)
- Correspondence - N.H. Crosby 1889-1892 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - D.F. Currie and Mrs. Florence Currie 1887 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - D to Dixon 1882-1912 (Box 4)
  Correspondents include: C. H. David, William G. David, Mrs. Homer C. (Daisy B.) Davenport, Homer Davenport, Julius G. Day, Richard DeLong, William H. Dempsey, T. Henry Dewey, Charles W. Dickel, Francis Dilleichux, J.S. Dixon
- Correspondence - Dole to Duryea 1879-1904 (Box 4)
  Correspondents include: Chales S. Dole, Charles B. Doll, A. B. Donelson, Webb Donnell, D. B. Doughty, Aug[ustus] C. Downing, C. W. Downing, Richard F. Downing, Sara W. Drake, Jont[.] Dresback, Will C. Dunn, Samuel B. Duryea.
- Correspondence - Foxhall A. Daingerfield, Attorney at Law, Harrisonburg, Virginia 1885-1886 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - J.W. May, M.D. of Patchen Stock Farm 1881-1887 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - James DeFray 1888-1889 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - William P. Dixon of Miller, Peckham & Dixon, Attorneys and Counsellors 1895-1902 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - George S. Doud of Doud, Son & Company 1884-1885 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - Frank H. Dunton, editor of Spirit of the Turf 1885-1892 (Box 4)
- Correspondence - E 1879-1901 (Box 5)
  Correspondents include: Annie H. Eastburn, William Easton, Marion J.B. Eddy, William Edwards, The Epoch, Drs. C. or H. Finn E[rmany], S.G. Evans, Maxwell Evarts, The Evening Telegraph
- Correspondence - Eastman Kodak Company 1901-1903 (Box 5)
- Correspondence Henry A. Egerton, includes pedigree of "Congo" 1887-1889 (Box 5)
- Correspondence - R.W. Evans, Petroleum Producer 1884 (Box 5)
- Correspondence - F 1880-1890 (Box 5)
  Correspondents include: William D. Fitzhugh, Edward D. Foote, Foote Brothers (includes pedigrees of "Badger Clay" and "Dr. Strong"), Charles E. Ford, O.R. Ford, W.C. France
- Correspondence - Francis P. Freeman of F.P. Freeman & Company, Bankers 1880-1889 (Box 5)
- Correspondence - G 1882-1898 (Box 5)
  Correspondents include: L.D. Gage, W.F. Gale, John Garnish, J.W. Garrett (per his secretary A.B. Crane), J.E. Gates, J.B. Gattshall, A.B. Gauss, Samuel Gibson, J.D. Giddings, C.M. Gilman, Miss E.B. Gilman, G. Gi[rsnobs], William M. Glaves, F.T. Glisan, S.H. Godfrey, G.H. Goodrich, J.M. Goodwin, M.J. Gordon, H.B. Gorham, Thomas H. Gorman, O.B. Gould, John M. Gray, J.W. Gray, D.W. Greene, Pliny Grover, D.S. Gurnsey
- Correspondence - Charles T. Goodwin 1884-1891 (Box 5)
- Correspondence - Willis F. Gove 1890-1891 (Box 5)
- Correspondence - Harry P. Gunn of Fashion Livery Stables 1886-1888 (Box 5)
- Correspondence - H to Hazard 1877-1903 (Box 5)
  Correspondents include: Charles H. Hall, John B. Hall, W.W. Hamilton, C.J. Hamlin, H.P. Hancock, John J. Hanley, George Harding, Harper Brothers, Harper & Martin, J.Low Harriman, George W. Harris, J.W. Hartzell, J.R. Havens, [] Hawley, Walter I. Hayes, Henry Haynes, Charles du Hays, C.D. Hayt, H. Hayward, J.H. Hazard
- Correspondence - Hegeman to Hopkins 1881-1903 (Box 5)
  Correspondents include: T.S. Hegeman, Winthrop Hegeman, H.B. Henderson, William H. Henry of The Rider and Driver, Charles H. Hepburn, Charles Griffin Herring, Ulysses Hertig, Hess, Townsend, and McClelland, Counsellors at Law, Samuel H. Hicks, Homer J. Hill, L.J. Hilton, H.L. Hodge, E.G. Holden, Mrs. George W. (E.A.) Holdridge, J.C. Holmes, William Holworthy, A.O. Hooker, B.C. Hopkins, David Hopkins, J.R. Hopkins
- Correspondence - Hotchkiss to Hyde 1879-1903 (Box 5)
  Correspondents include: Horace L. Hotchkiss, L.T. Houghton, W.A. Houghton, D. Houston, L.H. Howes, S.S. Howland, Amelia Dunbar Hunt, H.J. Drum Hunt, Herbert Huntington, J.B. Huntington, S.S. Huntley, O.P. Hurd, James T. Hyde
- Correspondence - Henry J.S. Hall 1902-1904 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - G.W. and John S. Hamlin 1882-1903 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - P.A. Hargous 1889 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Spencer R. Harpending 1879-1889 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - T.W. Harvey 1888 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - A.G. Hooley 1887-1904 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Herman Hoopes of Highland Farm, West Chester, Pennsylvania 1899-1904 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - W.H. Hughes 1903 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Allie Huntington, daughter of Randolph Huntington 1886-1901 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Archer M. Huntington (per H.E. Merrill) 1903-1904 (Box 6)
  These eight letters are all the same text, pertaining to a monthly check for $100 to the account of Mrs. C.P. Huntington
- Correspondence - Belle Huntington (Isabelle Huntington), daughter of Randolph Huntington 1881-1903 (Box 6)
  She moves to Quincy, Illinois, and folder includes one letter from Randolph to her, 1887 Jul 24.
- Correspondence - Charles W. Huntington 1879-1886 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Lizzie Huntington, wife of Randolph Huntington 1886-1890 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Nate Huntington, son of Randolph Huntington 1883-1891 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Randolph Huntington 1886-1891 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - Robert G.H. Huntington 1879?-1891 (Box 6)
- Correspondence - I-J 1882-1904 (Box 7)
  Correspondents include: E.J. Ingalsbe, E.[N.] Jackson, R.H. Jackson, George B. James of The American Cultivator and American Horse Breeder, Samuel M. Jarvis, William C. Jeffries, Alexander Jones, Charles H. Jones, O. Judd Company, publisher of American Agriculturalist
- Correspondence - W.A. Jemison 1889 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - Henry C. Jewett of Jewett Stock Farm 1881-1889 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - John G. Johnson 1889 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - K 1880-1905 (Box 7)
  Correspondents include: M.C. Keith, E.F. Kelley, Law Office of Kelly & MacRae, N.M. Kennedy, Mrs. John (Celestian M.) Kent, Charles H. Kerner, Madison Kimball, W.R. Kimball, Donald B. Kingshery, B.F. Kingsley, Edmund Kirby, Clifford Kirkpatrick, D. Knapp, V.J. Knapp, Alex C. Knealy of the New York Herald, A.D. Kniffin, J.A. Knowlton, Edward C. Kohn
- Correspondence - Peter C. Kellogg (& Company), Auctioneers and Dealers in Horses and Cattle 1883-1899 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - Frank N. Kondolf, son-in-law of Randolph after marrying Allie Huntington 1891-1896 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - Henry M. Kramrath 1894-1895 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - L 1879-1903 (Box 7)
  Correspondents include: George Lambert, John Landers, J.N. Lasher, Ariel Lathrop, Daniel S. Lathrop, Launder & Harter Livery, James A. Lawrence, Frank Learned, D. Carlos Leavens, Mortimer Levering, secretary of the American Shetland Pony Club, Stephen H. Little, William A. Little, Francis G. Lloyd, George G. Lobdell, Joseph Logle, John Samuel Long, W.D. Loomis, Atherton Loring, Vice President of the Library Bureau of Boston, James W. Love[hirer], Robert Luce, president of Horse and Stable, Cyrus Lukens, Persis R.R. Luk[is], A.G. Lyon
- Correspondence - J.S. Lewis 1880-1894 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - Library of Congress Copyright Office 1885 & 1904 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - Sara B. Linard 1891-1892 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - J.B. Lippincott Company, per A.J. Borie 1885-1890 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - Frederic A. Lucas of the United States National Museum 1884-1885 (Box 7)
- Correspondence - M to McMillan 1879-1904 (Box 8)
  Correspondents include: J. H. MacCormac, John Mack, P.C. Mackubin, Leslie E. Macleod, editor of The Horseman, M.J. MacMahon, Fred H. Mann, Stuart R. Mann, W.G. Markham, Mrs. F.W. Marshall, secretary for A.W. Drake, director of The Century Art Department, Robert H. Martin, W.R. H. Martin, John D. Masengil, Perry Mason & Company of The Youth's Companion, M.N. Matteson, re: his father, O.C. Matteson, William A. Matteson, James McAllister, B.R. McAlpine, R.M. McBride of Livestock Department, Country Life in America, Joseph W. McCall, G. McCleary, W.P. McCleery, McDonald, H.M. McDonald, H.C. McDowell, Henry McHugh, H.S. McKennan, S.W. McKibben, Henry McMillan, P. McMillan
- Correspondence - Meeker to Moore 1884-1904 (Box 8)
  Correspondents include: Jacob Meeker, Mrs. George A. (Laurie G.) Meyer, C.W. Mihills, Manly Miles, W.M. Millen, Charles Miller & Jospeh C. Sibley, Charles F. Mills, secretary of the American Association Live Stock Herd Book Secretaries in a letter to the American Arabian Horse Breeders' Association, Mrs. Anne C. Miner, W.H. Mink, Charles W. Mitchell, Francis B. Mitchell, J.W. Mitchell, George E. Molleson, John L. Moody, Moore & Company, Moore
- Correspondence - Morgan to Murray 1883-1900 (Box 8)
  Correspondents include: George O. Morgan, Miss Midy Morgan, reporter for The New York Times, W.P. Morgan, C.E. Morrison, William J. Morrison, William H. Morrow, Philip S. Moxom, Moyses Brothers, L.S. Mulford, Milton Mundy, Munn & Company, T.H. Munson, Mrs. Louise A.B. Murray
- Correspondence - L.B. Marcy of Losey & Marcy, Counselors at Law 1888-1889 (Box 8)
- H.D. McKinney, secretary and treasurer of the Northwestern Association of Trotting and Pacing Horse Breeders 1879-1889 (Box 8)
- Correspondence - H.C. Merwin, Counsellor at Law and contributor to the Boston Post 1887-1893 (Box 8)
- Correspondence - George A. Moody 1888-1890 (Box 8)
- Correspondence - John P. Munn 1886 (Box 8)
- Correspondence - Mutual Life Insurance Company 1888-1904 (Box 8)
- Correspondence - N to O 1876-1891 (Box 8)
  Correspondents include: Alexander Neave, G.W. Nelson, Peter Nelson, A.S. Newman, Rob D. North, F. O'Rourke, Joseph R. Oakden, Ira L. Otis
- Correspondence - S.E. Olivier 1889-1891, 3 folders (Box 8)
- Correspondence - Harrison G. Otis 1885-1886 (Box 8)
- Correspondence - P 1881-1891 (Box 9)
  Correspondents include: L.D. Packer, secretary of the National Association of Trotting Horse Breeders, Allen B. Palmer, C.G. Palmer, L.W. Parker, E.B. Parsons, R.W. Pearce, James H. Pennell, T.A. Perrin, John G. Perry, William H. Peters, John H. Phillips, N.H. Piffard, J.S. Pierson, A.H. Plato, T.D. Plumb, Charles H. Plummers, John T. Prentiss, J.R. Prescott, M.L. Prescott, D.W. Prime
- Correspondence - Simon W. Parlin of The American Cultivator, editor of American Horse Breeder, secretary of The New England Association of Trotting Horse Breeders 1886-1891 (Box 9)
- Correspondence - Theodore Cuyler Patterson 1894-1902 (Box 9)
- Correspondence - Henry Peterson 1885-1890, 2 folders (Box 9)
- Correspondence - J.E. Pierpont 1886-1887 (Box 9)
- Correspondence - James Potter 1884-1888, 3 folders (Box 9)
- Correspondence - James Potter 1889-1892, 3 folders (Box 10)
- Correspondence - Stewart L. Purdy 1884-1891 (Box 10)
- Correspondence - R 1880-1891 (Box 10)
  Correspondents include: Miners Raplee, John T. Rapple, J.J. Redman, G.G. Reed, R. Richardson, D.C. Robbins, C.F. Roberts, W.A. Roberts, J.R. Robinson, George A. Roedes, L.J. Rose, J.J. Row, B.S. Runyan, H.P. Ruppell, William Rushmore, C.S. Russell, J.B. Russell, S. Russell
- Correspondence - J.A.P. and Fanny N. Ramsdell 1893-1901 (Box 10)
- Correspondence - H.C.F. Randolph 1883-1888 (Box 10)
- Correspondence - John J. Riker 1900-1903 (Box 10)
- Correspondence - I.P. Roberts of Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station 1888-1889 (Box 10)
- Correspondence - Charles E. Rogers 1900-1901 (Box 10)
- Correspondence - S to Smedley 1885-1905 (Box 11)
  Correspondents include: J.H. Sanders Publishing Company re: The Breeder's Gazette, William H. Sargent, Samuel B. Schieffelin, E.H. Schley, A.R. Scott & Company of The Livingston Republican, Charles Scribner's Sons, J.W. Seabrook, S.H. Seamans, B.F. Sells, M.E. Servis, secretary and treasurer of The New York State Trotting Horse Breeders' Association, William H. Seward, George A. Shaw, E. Newlon Shepard, E.T. Sherman, R.R. Sinclair of Harper & Brothers' Editorial Rooms, William Sinnock, Jones Smedley
- Correspondence - Smith to Stuyvesant 1883-1901 (Box 11)
  Correspondents include: Smith & Hulett, A.V. Smith, Asa Smith, C[...] B. Smith, C.W. Smith, Charles H. Smith, D.B. Smith, Elizur Smith, George E. Smith, Jacob M. Smith, Stephen W. Smith, William H. Smith, Will L. Smith, John Splan, H.S. Stafford, Senator Stanford, C.B. Stanley, J.B. Starmard(?), W.H. Stith, Wallace G. Stiles, William O. Stillman, Carl Stoeckel, R.J. Stukey of The Western Horseman, John R. Stuyvesant
- Correspondence - Joseph Cairn Simpson, editor of Breeder and Sportsman 1884-1890 (Box 11)
- Correspondence - J. Adams Smith, U.S. Navy Pay Office, Department of Provisions and Clothing 1880-1889, 2 folders (Box 11)
- Correspondence - Smithsonian Institution, J.A. Turner, Librarian, Spencer F. Baird, Secretary 1886 (Box 11)
- Correspondence - John Gilmer Speed 1901 (Box 11)
- Correspondence - O.H. Stevens 1886-1891 (Box 11)
- Correspondence - T 1886-1904 (Box 11)
  Correspondents include: S.J. Tallmadge, Emma Taylor, John G. Taylor, Samuel W. Taylor, Jr., editor and publisher of The Rider and Driver, Thomas Taylor, N.M. Terry, Edward M. Tesson, John Boyd Thacker, J. Gaillard Thomas, Allen W. Thomson, E.H. Thorp of The Middlebury Register, F.J. Thorpe, Louis Comfort Tiffany, E.M. Townsend, W.W. Tucker, Edward Tyler, William R. Tyler
- Correspondence - William S. Taylor 1887-1888 (Box 11)
- Correspondence - B.W. Tinan 1890 (Box 12)
- Correspondence - John D. Tompkins 1886-1891 (Box 12)
- Correspondence - Howard H. Tozer 1896-1904 (Box 12)
- Correspondence - P. Traynor 1899-1900 (Box 12)
- Correspondence - Luther H. Tucker of Luther Tucker & Sons, editors and publishers of The Cultivator and Country Gentleman 1886-1908 (Box 12)
- Correspondence - U to V 1883-1900 (Box 12)
  Correspondents include: L.C. Underhill of Sportsman, W.J. Underwood, Union Publishing Company, L.S. Van Vliet, Frank Vanderbilt, John Vanderbilt, R. Vandeventer
- Correspondence - Unidentified 1880 Dec 12 (Box 12)
  This Albany correspondent discusses the pedigrees of "Harry Clay" and "Clay Pilot."
- Correspondence - John E. Van Etten 1885-1886 (Box 12)
- Correspondence - Nelson Varney 1891, 1902-1904 (Box 12)
- Correspondence -W to Whyland 1881-1904 (Box 12)
  Correspondents include: B.C. Wakely, W.D. Walcott, S.P. Waldo, Charles C. Walker, W.A. Walker, George K. Ward, Riley Ward, J. Kearney Warren, Jr., R.W.G. Welling, Isaac S. Wells, L.A. Wendell, N. Wheeler, S.H. Wheeler, Thomas J. Wheeler, R.E. White, Willard White, John L. Whiton, A.E. Whyland
- Correspondence - Wier to Wynkorp 1879-1904 (Box 12)
  Correspondents include: F.A. Wier, A.H. Willard, E.L. Williams, E.P. Williams, Henry Williams, Jr., I. Williams, J.D. Willis, D.G. Wilmarth, Charles Wilson, William H. Wilson, Joseph W. Wilstach, John E. Winans, William T. Withers, Jr., Lester Witherspoon, John J. Wise, C.W. Witters, B.B. Wood, Franc Ogilvy Wood, W.T. Wood, Woodard & Harbison, Miss L.E. Wooden, J.S. Woodhouse, E.L. Woodside, C.A. Woodward, D.M. Worley, T.S. Wynkorp
- Correspondence - Fred C. Warren of George Warren & Sons, Laurel Hill Stock Farm 1889-1902 (Box 12)
  Includes pedigree and terms of service of "Black Henry," "King Morgan," "Artillery," and information on the trotting stallion "Billy Patterson" and "Fallis 4781".
- Correspondence - Francis H. Weeks 1890-1893 (Box 13)
- Correspondence - P.B. West of Studio Stock Farm 1889-1891 (Box 13)
- Correspondence - Louis de V. Wilder 1903-1904 (Box 13)
  Includes information on his entertainer son, Marshall P. Wilder
- Correspondence - X,Y, Z 1885 (Box 13)
  Includes: L.M. Young, with information on "Clay Pilot" and "Captain Lewis"
- Financial Papers 1833, 1879-1902 (Box 13)
  Arranged chronologically.
- News clippings re Horses 1905 Sep, n.d. (Box 13)
- Pedigrees and Miscellaneous Material 1889 & 1892, n.d. (Box 13)
- Reviews of History of Leopard and Linden, General Grant's Arabian Stallions by Randolph Huntington 1886-1887, n.d. (Box 13)